Guide to the Corcoran Gallery of Art and Corcoran College of Art + Design, Corcoran Gallery of Art Development and Membership records 1869-2010 COR0003.2.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Statistics, 1964-1978; Series 8
  This series contains statistical materials on development, membership, and contributions. Statistical categories include 1) attendance/ admissions; 2) budgets (Development); 3) category fluxes (Membership categories); 4) contributions reports; "5) Membership Daily Receipt reports/transmittals and logs (Nov. 1972-Aug.1973 logs were destroyed by water damage); 6) Membership renewals; 7) membership reports (monthly tallies); 8) new membership sources; 9) progress reports, and 10) transmittals/contributions (restricted or unrestricted). Items are arranged alphabetically by statistical category, and thereafter chronologically.
  - Attendance/Admissions (data from 1966-), 1970; Series 8 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Membership & Development (see also Subjects: Bulk Mailings-Cost Estimates), 1968; Series 8 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Category Fluxes (Membership Categories), 1974; Series 8 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Contributions Reports, 1976; Series 8 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Contributions Reports, 1977; Series 8 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Contributions Reports (data from 1960-), 1971-1975; Series 8 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Gift Reports, 1975; Series 8 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Gift Reciepts, 1965-1974; Series 8 (Box 9, Folders 1-4)
  - Membership Daily Reciept Reports/Transmittals, 1973 September-1977 March; Series 8 (Box 9, Folders 5-14)
  - Membership Daily Reciept Reports/Transmittals-Log Form, 1970 January-1974 August; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Membership Renewals, 1972 March-1974 February; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Membership Reports (Monthly Tallies), 1972-1977; Series 8 (Box 9, Folders 17-19)
  - New Membership Sources, 1976 April; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Progress Reports, 1974 November-1975 February; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Transmittals/Contributions-Restricted, 1977 May-1978 April; Series 8 (Box 9, Folders 22-24)
  - Transmittals/Contributions-Restricted, 1975 January-1977 April; Series 8 (Box 9, Folders 25-27)
  - Transmittals/Contributions-Unestricted, 1975 January-1978 April; Series 8 (Box 9, Folders 28-35)
  - Transmittals/Contributions-Restricted & Unrestricted, 1974 September-December; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous, Undated; Series 8 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Publications, Circa 1959-1989; Series 9
  This series contains general Corcoran and Corcoran membership brochures, the Corcoran Calendar (1948- } and the Corcoran Newsletter (three issues published, Fall 1980-Spring 1981). Also included is a special newsletter, Opportunities for the Corcoran, published in June 1977 in conjunction with the "Opportunities" fund raising campaign of Summer 1977. Materials are organized by title/type, and thereafter chronologically. These publications are located with other general Gallery publications for easy access.
  - General Corcoran Brochures, Undated; Series 9 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - General Corcoran Brochures (Brief Descr. + Membership Info), Undated; Series 9 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Membership Christmas Gifts Brochures, Undated; Series 9 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Reciprocal Membership Brochures, Undated; Series 9 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Exhibition invitations, Undated; Series 9 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Corcoran Newsletter (Issues 1-3), 1980 Fall-1981 Spring; Series 9 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Opportunities for the Corcoran, 1987 July; Series 9 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - [Publications], 1959-1960; Series 9 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - [Publications], 1960-1969; Series 9 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - The Friends (Membership Benefits), Circa 1970-1989; Series 9 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Unprocessed records, 1976-2010; Series 10
  Materials transferred to the Corcoran archives after the mid-1980s remain unprocessed, and have not been integrated with the existing records although they have been maintained in record groups according to the office that made the transfer. Box-level descriptions of the records, included below, are the only information that is currently available in most cases.